

Muhammad Difa' Sulthon Diani

Mobile Developer / Front End Developer

Bekasi, Indonesia (17510) | (+62) 857-7677-5939 | mdifasulthon@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/difasulthon | github.com/difasulthon medium.com/@mdifasulthon

About Me

I have about 4 years of experience in developing and maintaining mobile applications using React Native. I have a strong fundamental in Javascript/TypeScript programming language. Based on these experiences and skills, I was able to contribute to working on a web app with ReactJS and working on the back end with NodeJS. I have experience working on application development with clean code, unit testing, and type checking to write readable and maintainable code. I have the ability to work with agile methods and communicate well with team members such as Back End Developer, QA/Tester, Product Owner, or other stakeholders to achieve goals and deliver the best software product.

Experience

Jenius / PT. Bank Tabungan Pensiunan Nasional - Front End Developer

January 2022 - present

- Involved in development and maintaining Transaction feature such as Send It and QRIS Payment and Credit Card feature at Jenius app, and Transfer feature at Jenius Lite app.
- Implement maintainable code with unit testing and maintain code coverage above 95%.
- Contribute to review pull request from another front end developer.
- Involved in development at jenius dashboard web for credit card sales team.
- Involved in a little research related to new relic alert for Jenius Lite app.
- Involved in assisting the technical leader in interviewing new joiner candidates.
- Become a buddy for new front end joiner.
- Tech stack: Javascript, Typescript, React Native, ReactJS, ExpressJS, GraphQL, Openshift
- Tools: VS Code, Reactotron, Flipper, Bitbucket, Postman, Jenkins, Jira, OCP

PT. Xsis Mitra Utama - Software Engineer

December 2019 - December 2021

- Involved in development and maintaining Onekalbe Mobile in PT. Kalbe Farma
- Involved in development and maintaining several parts in Onekalbe Mobile such as Training Attendance, GA Online, and Asset Management Online.
- Involved in maintaing H2Active app for product sales and employee attendance by medical representative Kalbe Farma.
- Become mentor for Mobile Developer intern from Bintang Toedjoe.
- Tech stack: Jevascript, React Native, SQL
- Tools: VS Code, Swagger, Microsift SQL Server, PMO Sheet

Freelance - React Native Developer

January 2024 - present

• Involved in development unreleased apps for manage minisoccer community in Brunei Darussalam.

- · Create automation release development build for iOS and Android using fastlane for testing.
- Tech stack: Typescript, React Native

September 2023 - October 2023

- Involved in developing and mantaining Smartstays app for hotel service management delivered through smart tvs.
- Tech stack: Typescript, React Native TVOS

August 2021

- Involved in developing and maintaining Bintang app for asset management of Star tabloid from MD Entertainment
- Tech stack: Javascript, React Native

Education -

Binus University (Online Learning) - Bachelor's Degree of Information System

September 2020 - September 2022

• GPA: 3,93 / 4,00

Telkom University - Associate's Degree of Computer Technology

August 2016 - October 2019

• GPA: 3,80 / 4,00

Course -

Udemy - React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB - The MERN Fullstack Guide

June 2020

- Learning ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, and MongoDB fundamental
- Practical on development several simple full stack web app using ReactJS and ExpressJS
- Tech stack: Javascript, ReactJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB
- Tools: VS Code, Postman

Udemy - React Native: The Practical Guide

February 2020

- Learning ReactJS and React Native Fundamental
- Practical on development several simple React Native apps
- Tech stack: Javascript, React Native
- Tools: VS Code, Expo app

Xsis Academy by PT. Xsis Mitra Utama - Kotlin for Android

October 2019 - November 2019

- Completing course of Kotlin foundation with score 73 / 100.
- Completing course of Kotlin technology for Android and SQL.
- Tech stack: Kotlin, SQL
- Tools: Intellij, Android Studio